{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following is the necessary step for cultivating the microorganisms?", "opta": "Preparing a culture medium for the growth of microorganisms", "optb": "Sterilizing in order to eliminate all living microorganisms in vessel", "optc": "Inoculating the microorganisms in the prepared medium", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For most bacteria, the optimum pH for growth lies between", "opta": "6.5-7.5", "optb": "3.5-4.5", "optc": "4.5-5.5", "optd": "5.5-6.5", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an abiotic elicitors?", "opta": "UV irradiation", "optb": "Osmotic shock", "optc": "Heavy metal ions", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Suspension cultures consist of cells and cell aggregates, growing dispersed in", "opta": "liquid medium", "optb": "solid nutrient medium", "optc": "solid or liquid medium", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thiobacillus thiooxidans has an optimum pH of", "opta": "2.0-3.5", "optb": "0.5-6.0", "optc": "6.5-7.5", "optd": "9.0-9.5", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Balanced growth is defined as", "opta": "cultures undergoing balanced growth while maintaining a constant chemical composition", "optb": "balancing the growth while controlling the pH", "optc": "balancing the growth while controlling the temperature", "optd": "balancing the growth while changing the nutrient composition", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Semi-solid media, prepared with agar at concentrations of 0.5% or less are useful for the cultivation of", "opta": "Microaerophillic bacteria", "optb": "Lactobacilli", "optc": "E.coli", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cell mass can be measured optically by determining the amount of light scattered by a suspension of cells. The measurements are usually at a wavelength of", "opta": "300-400nm", "optb": "400-500nm", "optc": "500-600nm", "optd": "600-700nm", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an indirect method for the measurement of cell mass?", "opta": "Nutrient composition", "optb": "Cell dry weight", "optc": "Viscosity", "optd": "Heat evolution", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Callus cultures are amorphous cell aggregates arising from the unorganized growth of explants on an", "opta": "liquid medium", "optb": "solid nutrient medium", "optc": "aseptic solid nutrient medium", "optd": "solid or liquid medium", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The protoplast can be used to", "opta": "modify genetic information", "optb": "create plant hybrid", "optc": "study plant viral infections", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is incorrect?", "opta": "Mammalian cells are larger and more complex than microorganisms", "optb": "Their growth rate is very fast compared to microorganisms", "optc": "Mammalian cells are fragile", "optd": "Most animal cells only grow when attached to surface", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The size of a single plant cell is usually within the range of", "opta": "10-20\u03bcm in diameter and 25-100\u03bcm long", "optb": "20-40\u03bcm in diameter and 100-200\u03bcm long", "optc": "40-60\u03bcm in diameter and 200-300\u03bcm long", "optd": "60-80\u03bcm in diameter and 300-400\u03bcm long", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is incorrect?", "opta": "Plant cells are larger than the bacterial or fungus cells", "optb": "Plant cells tend to grow in clumps", "optc": "Plant cells are less sensitive to shear than microbial cells", "optd": "Plant cells are more genetically unstable than microbial cells", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The archaebacterium Halobacterium, an extreme halophile, and Sulfolobus, a thermoacidophile, can be cultured in the presence of antibiotics such as streptomycin and chloramphenicol because", "opta": "they contain ether-linked isoprenoids in their plasma membrane", "optb": "they lack murein in their cell wall", "optc": "they contain 80S, as opposed to 70S, ribosomes", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The isolation of the gonorrhoea - causing organisms, Neisseria gonorrhoeae,from a clinical specimen is facilitated by the use of media containing", "opta": "cellulose", "optb": "certain antibiotics", "optc": "succinate", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Anchorage -dependent cells require", "opta": "wettable surface for growth", "optb": "dry surface for growth", "optc": "either (a) or (b)", "optd": "nothing to do with the surface", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stringent anaerobes can be grown in a media by taking special measure as", "opta": "boiling the media for several minutes", "optb": "addition of cysteine", "optc": "passing through oxygen-free nitrogen", "optd": "any of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Radical shifts in pH can be prevented by incorporating", "opta": "a buffer", "optb": "an oxidizing agent", "optc": "a reducing agent", "optd": "any of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}